<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Alberto Fuentes Arce</title>
    <link>https://AlbertoFuentesArce.github.io/Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Alberto Fuentes Arce</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://AlbertoFuentesArce.github.io/Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Loan Default Prediction using ANNs</title>
      <link>https://AlbertoFuentesArce.github.io/Portfolio/post/loan-default-prediction-using-dnns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://AlbertoFuentesArce.github.io/Portfolio/post/loan-default-prediction-using-dnns/</guid>
      <description>This case study covers the entire machine learning pipeline in an attempt to produce useful models with Deep Neural Networks (DNNs) that can be used in the loan industry. The study focuses on minimizing financial risk for the lending company. By conducting an in-depth Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA), we examine the relationships between variables. In the preprocessing stage, we transform the data and perform feature engineering to enhance our model predictions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EUR/USD Exchange Rate Forecasting with Monte Carlo Simulations</title>
      <link>https://AlbertoFuentesArce.github.io/Portfolio/post/eurusd-exchange-rate-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://AlbertoFuentesArce.github.io/Portfolio/post/eurusd-exchange-rate-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>This project uses the Geometric Brownian Motion (GBM) Model to predict the future evolution of the EUR/USD exchange rate. GBM is a stochastic process commonly used in financial modeling to simulate the random movement of assets such as stock prices, exchange rates, and commodity prices. This project was developed in a real risk management scenario to assess the risk that a client had in his derivatives portfolio. Other analyses, such as VAR, were also performed.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
